Guide to the Leander E. Keck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Leander E. Keck Papers
1950-2013
RG 256
Yale University Divinity School Library
10.5
(25 boxes)
Writings, lectures, course-related materials, and correpondence document the life and work of Leander E. Keck, who served as Dean of the Yale Divinity School from 1979 to 1989 and Winkley Professor of Biblical Theology from 1979, Emeritus as of January 1998.
Keck, Leander E., 1928-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Leander E. Keck, 2013
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
For additional biographical documentation, see Series V.
1928 Mar 3 Born near Washburn, North Dakota
1949 B.A., Linfield College
1953 B.D., Andover-Newton Theological School
1955-1956 Study in Kiel and Gottingen, Germany
1957 Ph.D., Yale University
1957-1959 Instructor, Biblical History, Wellesley College
1959-1972 Assistant Professor, Associate Professor, Professor at Vanderbilt Divinity School
1964-1965 Postdoctoral research, Tubingen, Germany
1971 Visiting Professor, Union Theological Seminary, Manila, Philippines
1971 Postdoctoral research, Cambridge, England
1972-1979 Professor and Chairman of Division of Religion in Graduate School, Emory University
1975 S.T.D., Bethany College
1976 Postdoctoral research, Cambridge, England
1979-1989 Dean, Winkley Professor of Biblical Theology, Yale Divinity School
1980 D. Litt., Atlantic Christian College
1980 D.H.L., Linfield College
1986 D.D., Texas Christian University
1987 L.L.D., Davidson College
1992 Beecher Lectures, Yale Divinity School
1998- Winkley Professor Emeritus of Biblical Theology, Yale Divinity School
Scope and Contents
This collection provides documentation of Leander E. Keck's long career as a New Testament scholar, professor, and theological education administrator. His many speaking engagements, publications, and engagement in the scholarly community are well documented. These are not the official archives of Keck's tenure as Dean of the Yale Divinity School, which are held by the University Archives, but insights into the life of the Divinity School are available in correspondence and course-related materials.
Arrangement
I. Lectures, Sermons, Talks
II. Writings
III. Course-related Material
IV. Correspondence
V. Biographical Documentation
Bible. New Testament -- Study and teaching; Theology -- Study and teaching; Keck, Leander E., 1928-; Yale University. Divinity School
- Lectures/Sermons/Talks, Series I
  - "Exegesis as a Theological Discipline" - Inaugural address, Vanderbilt Divinity School, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Exegesis and the Quest for a New Testament Theology" - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School., 1963 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Gospel in the Contemporary World" - Vanderbilt Conference on the Ministry, 1963 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Sacred and the Profane"; "Men and the Man"; "The Rites of Participation" - New England Baptist Student Movement Lectures, Grotonwood, Massachusetts, 1963 November 30- December 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Die Zusammenarbeit Von Christen & Juden in Amerika" - Tübingen and Regensburg, 1965 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Christians' Mission as Church?" - American Baptist Consultation on Leadership Development, Camp Sunnybrook, Pennsylvania, 1965 November 30 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "The Irrelevance and Relevance of the Historical Jesus" - Revised Manuscript, The Thomas Kepler Memorial Lectures, Oberlin Graduate School of Theology, 1965 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Book of Acts" and "Mandate to Witness", Union Church, Berea, KY, 1966 September (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The New Testament and Worship", 1966 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "N.T and Tradition - Churchly and Anti-Churchly Character of the NT" - Louisville Presbyterian Seminary, 1966 Dec (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "For the Sake of Witness", Berkeley Baptist Divinity School Commencement in Thousand Oaks Baptist Church, Berkeley, California, 1967 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Exegetical Analysis of Matt. 5:17-48", Open Theological Conference, Green Lake, Wisconsin, 1967 July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Old Bible in Today's World" and "The Layman and His Bible" - 1st Christian Church, Chattanooga, 1967 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Jesus and the Spectrum of Contemporary Judaism" and "Jesus and Judaism as Jesus Lived It - Part Two" - The Temple and 1st Presbyterian Church, Nashville, 1967 November 2; 1967 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "New Testament History and Literature" Lectures - 1st Christian Church, Vanderbilt Program, Huntsville, Alabama, 1967 (Fall) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Is the Bible Still Relevant for Christian Ethics? A Debate" - debate with Jim Sellers - Vanderbilt Divinity School, 1968 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Apocalyptic and the New Testament" - The Association of Disciples for Theological Discussion, Thompson Retreat House, Webster Groves, Missouri, 1968 November 8-10 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Reflections on the Ethos of a Divinity School" - Vanderbilt, 1968 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "What is the New Testament"; "The Anti-churchly Character of the NT"; "The New Testament as a Cultural Event" - Bailey Lectures, Berkeley Baptist Divinity School, 1969 January 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "What is the New Testament"; "The Anti-churchly Character of the NT"; "The New Testament as a Cultural Event" - Bailey Lectures, Berkeley Baptist Divinity School (Second copy), 1969 January 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Horizons of the Church's Life: The Sermon on the Mount" - Consultation on Church Union, Atlanta, 1969 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Asking and Hearing: The Search for an Adequate Approach" Lecture I; "The New Righteousness Among Men (5:17-48)" Lecture II -- The Sermon on the Mount Lectures - S. Dak. and N. Dak. U. Methodist and Virginia Methodists, 1969 February, October (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Jesus' Right to Represent Us Before God: The Epistle to the Hebrews" (Lecture I); "Jesus' Right to Represent God: The Gospel of John" (Lecture II); "Jesus and the Righteousness of Men: Matthew" (Lecture III); "Jesus and the Righteousness of God: Paul" (Lecture IV) - Theological Lectures, University of Winnipeg, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Jesus and the Righteousness of Men: Matthew" (Lecture III); "Jesus and th Righteousness of God: Paul" (Lecture IV) - The Man Jesus in the NT series, Winnipeg (Second copy), 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Cross and the Fidelity of God to the Past" (Lecture I); "Resurrection and the Fidelity of God to the Future" (Lecture II); "The Freedom of the Dead: Rom 6:6-11"; "The Freedom of the Living" - Caleb Davies Lectures, The Graduate Seminary, Phillip University, Enid, Oklahoma, 1970 February 17-19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Cross and the Fidelity of God to the Past" (Lecture I); "Resurrection and the Fidelity of God to the Future" (Lecture II) - Caleb Davies Lectures, The Graduate Seminary, Phillip University, Enid, Oklahoma (Second Copy), 1970 February 17-19 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Caleb Davies Lectures, The Graduate Seminary, Phillip University, Enid, Oklahoma (Correspondence), 1970 February 17-19 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Heritage of Bultmann" - Nebraska Wesleyan University, 1970 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Individual and the State in Biblical Perspective" - Vine St. Christian Church, Nashville, 1970 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Our Present Vocation" - Durham Chapel, Emory University (2 copies enclosed), 1973 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Biblical Basis for the Church's Life and Work in the World" An Address Presented to Church Women United in Dallas, Park Cities Baptist Church, Dallas, Texas, 1973 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Lazarus in the Pulpit, or Can the Preacher be Revived?" (Lecture I); "The Canon in the Pulpit, or When is Preaching Biblical?" (Lecture II); "Lazarus in the Pew, or Can Preaching Revive the Church?" (Lecture III); "The Parable in the World, or How do we Preach Jesus?" (Lecture IV) -H.I. Hester Lectures, Midwestern Baptist Theological Seminary, Kansas City, Missouri, 1973 March 6-9 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Paul's View of Freedom: Its Potential and Limitations" - Little Theater, Mountainlair, Tuesday, April 3, 1973; "Interpretations of Man in the New Testament" - Collegiate Rooms, Mountainlair, Wednesday, April 4, 1973 - West Virginia University, 1973 April 3-4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Jesus and Contemporary Heresy" - Good Friday Reflections, Mercer University, 1973 April (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Power in the N.T." - Glenn Memorial Church, Emory, 1973 September (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "The Legacy of David Friedrich Strauss" - Presidential Address, Southern Region AAR/SBL, Chattanooga, Tenn., 1974 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Liberation of NT Christology" - Methodist Theological School, Ohio, 1975 February (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Struggles for Freedom and Fidelity: Studies in the Acts of the Apostles" (Lecture I); "Breakthrough to Mission" (Lecture II); "The Decisive Struggle for Freedom and Fidelity" (Lecture III); "What to do with Paul?" (Lecture IV) - Four lectures on Acts, Furman University, 1974 July 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "The Vocation of Being Articulate" - Schumate Lecture, Lynchburg College, 1975 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "The Moral Aim of Knowledge" - Baccalaureate Sermon, Bethany College, 1975 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Vocation of the Church in the Bicentennial" - Druid Hills Presbyterian Church, Atlanta, Georgia, 1976 January (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Convocation Sermon" - Candler School of Theology, Atlanta, Georgia, 1976 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Bible and Christian Worship" - Union Theological Seminary, Richmond, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Jackson Lecturer for Minister's Week - Perkins School of Theology, Southern Methodist University, McFarlin Memorial Auditorium, Dallas, TX (Programs only), 1978 February 6-9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jackson Lectures - "The Bible in the Church" and "The Canon and Christian Worship" - Perkins School of Theology, Southern Methodist University, McFarlin Memorial Auditorium, Dallas, TX, 1978 February 6-9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "The Ethics of the Gospel According to Matthew" - Wesley Uniting Church, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Keck's Farewell from Candler Theological School, 1979 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 3a)
  - "Jesus in New Testament Christology" - The F.J. Cato Lecture, The Uniting Church in Australia (2 lectures), 1979 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Convocation "Celebrating a Concordance", Louisville, KY, 1979 April 23 (Box 3, Folder 4a)
  - "A Word Among Us Theologians" - Convocation Sermon of the One Hundred and Fifty-ninth Year - Yale Divinity School, Marquand Chapel, 1979 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "The Church in the 80s" - 1st Cong. Church, Cheshire, CT, Jan 1980; "The Church's Work in the 80s" - 1st Cong. Church, Old Greenwich, CT, Nov 30, 1980, 1980 Jan, Nov 30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Jesus in the New Testament", "Jesus Right to Represent God: John", "Jesus and the Righteousness of God: Paul" - Shaffer Lectures, Yale Divinity School, 1980 February (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Shaffer Lectures, Yale Divinity School (Correspondence only), 1980 February (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Christian College Seventy-eight Annual Commencement (Commencement program), 1980 May 11 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Baccalaureate Address, Linfield College, Melrose Auditorium (Program only), 1980 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "The Moral Meaning of Politics: Some Reflections" - Texas Christian University, Baccalaureate Commencement Address, Daniel-Meyer Coliseum, 1980 August 8 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "The Moral Meaning of Politics: Some Reflections" - Texas Christian University, Baccalaureate Commencement Address, Daniel-Meyer Coliseum (Picture and program only), 1980 August 8 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - A White Protestant's Response - Ecumenical Unity Rally: A Religious Affirmation of our Pluralism within the American Democratic Tradition, Center Church on the New Haven Green, 1980 September 13 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Preaching from the New Testament" - The 1980 Ezra Squier Tipple and Frances Youngker Vosburgh Lectures and Theological School Alumni Association Annual Meeting and Banquet, The Theological School, Drew University, 1980 October 15-16 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Is the New Testament a Field of Study? Or from Outler to Overbeck and Back" - Keynote Speaker, Special Session of the Southwest Seminar on the Development of Early Catholic Christianity honoring Albert Cook Outler, University of Dallas, 1980 November 9 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Theological Education in the 80s" - Pacific School of Religion, Berkeley, California, 1981 May (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "The Community of Faith and its Canon" - Otwell Retirement Dinner, Pacific School of Religion, 1981 May (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "The End is the Beginning" (Sermon) - Central Presbyterian Church, Montclair, New Jersey, 1981 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Reflections on Radical Right in Religion" - Lay School of Religion, New Haven, 1981 October (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Some Reflections on Gratitude" - The Kiwanis Club of New Haven, 1981 November 25 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "The End is the Beginning" - The Mount Carmel Congregational Church, United Church of Christ, Mount Carmel, Connecticut, 1982 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "The Danger and Opportunity of Using the Bible as a Moral Guide" - John Newman Summer Institute, Wisconsin, 1982 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Winston Salem" - Christian Church, North Carolina, 1982 April 24-25 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Biblical Preaching as Divine Wisdom" - National Ecumenical Symposium on Preaching, Word of God Institute, Sanctuary of Cannon Chapel - Emory University, 1982 December 28-29 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Jerusalem: City and Symbol" - Yale University, 1983 March 24-26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Seminary and Church: Shared Dilemmas, Shared Opportunities" - Brite Divinity School, 1983 May 6 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Faith the Watches and Expects" - Church of the Redeemer, New Haven, 1983 Aug (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "No to Utopianism" - Utopia Symposium, Marquand Chapel, Yale Divinity School, 1984 March 30 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Bones, Corpse and Spirit: Ezekiel 37: 1-14, Romans 8:11-19, John 11: 1-4, 17, 34-53" - University Public Worship and The Church of Christ, Yale University, Dwight Memorial Chapel, 1984 April 8 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "1 Cor. 3:19-23" - Mead Memorial Chapel, Middlebury College, Middlebury, Vermont, 1984 May 6 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Christ and Salvation" - Would You Believe? Battell Lectures, The Church of Christ, Yale University, 1984 October 7 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Yale's Divinity School" - AYA program, 1984 October 18 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Yale's Divinity School" - AYA program (Correspondence only), 1984 October 18 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Meditation, Chapel Service (Program only), 1985 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Perkins Lectures: "The Gospel of God and the God of the Gospel" (Lecture I); "Beyond 'Live and Let Live'" (Lecture II); "The Otherness of God" (Lecture III); "When Trust Rectifies" (Lecture IV); "The Failure and Necessity of Law" (Lecture V); "The Moral Meaning of the Spirit" (Lecture VI) - First United Methodist Church, Wichita Falls, Texas, 1986 March 9-11 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Perkins Lectures, First United Methodist Church, Wichita Falls, Texas (Correspondence only), 1986 March 9-11 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sermon by Leander Keck - The First Congregational Church in Bloomfield (Program only), 1986 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - SNTS, Atlanta, GA, 1986 August 11 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Claiming the Future" - Graduate and Professional Assembly, Yale University, 1986 September 8 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sermon - Church of Christ Congregational, Granby, Massachusetts, Service of Installation the Reverend Michael S. Bennett (Program and correspondence only), 1986 September 14 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Ministry" - 1st Cong. Church, Old Greenwich, 1986 September 26 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sermon - First Church of Christ, New Britain, CT (Program only), 1986 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Paul in the Pulpit" - Clergy Day, Meriden, 1986 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Academe and Steeple: Shared Vocation" - Convocation Address, Davidson College, North Carolina, 1987 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Convocation address, Davidson College, North Carolina (Correspondence), 1987 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sermon - University Public Worship and the Church of Christ, Battell Chapel (Program only), 1987 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Disciple Video Project text, Nashville, TN, 1987 April 6 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "In Honor of J. Louis Martyn" - Address, Biblical Jubilee, Union Theological Seminary Sesquicentennial, New York, 1987 April 8-9 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Sermon - The First Church in Windsor, United Church of Christ, Windsor, CT (Program and correspondence only), 1987 April 26 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sermon - Rededication Service, The First Church of Christ, Woodbridge, CT, 1987 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Paul: Problem and Promise" - Fifth Annual Dr. Lloyd H. Rising Theological Lecture, First United Methodist Church, Pittsburg, Kansas, 1987 October 21 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Jewish Apocalyptic Eschatology and Paul's Letter to the Romans: A Discussion" - Columbia Seminar, 1988 March 25 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Paul: Problem and Promise" - The Thomas L. King Memorial Lecture, Washburn University, Topeka, Kansas, 1988 March 27-28 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sermon- The Congregational Church of Salisbury, United Church of Christ, Salisbury, CT, 1988 April 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pastoral Prayer - 350th Anniversary, Center Church, The First Church of Christ, New Haven, CT, 1988 April 24 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Paul: Problem and Promise", "The Work of a Biblical Scholar", "Paul's Understanding of Freedom" - 12th Annual Spring Theological Lectures, Lutheran Campus Ministry, Buffalo, NY, 1988 April 25 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Arts in Relation to the Nature and Content of Theological Education" - Yale ISM, New Haven, CT, 1988 April 29 - May 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Paul: Problem and Promise" - Walla Walla College, College Place, Washington (Correspondence only), 1988 May 8-10 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Paul's Understanding of the Gospel as the Good News of God's Freedom" - Scripture Institute, Saint Joseph College, West Hartford, CT, 1988 June 27-30 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Paul's Idea of Freedom" - The Wofford College Lecture Series in Religion, Ethics and Society, Wofford College, Spartanburg, SC, 1989 April 27 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Jesus and Salvation" - Chi Rho Series, Eugene, Oregon, 1990 October 26-28 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tribute - A Christian Service of Praise and Worship Celebrating the Life of Ruth Esther Cox Lantz; Tribute to J. Edwards Lantz - Glenn Memorial UMC, Emory University Campus, Atlanta, GA, 1990 December 23; 1991 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Toward the Renewal of "Mainline" Protestantism" - Beecher Lectures, Yale Divinity School, Winter Convocation Opening Service, Marquand Chapel, Yale Divinity School, 1992 February 10-13 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Beecher Lectures (Correspondence), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Beecher Lectures - Contract, 1992 May (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Paul as Thinker" - Achtemeier Fest. (Text), 1992 April 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Worship" - Conference of Ministers of Larger Churches in Atlanta, GA, 1993 April 13-15 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Confident in the Gospel: The Non-Negotiable Center" - The William W. Brady Memorial Lectures, Northern Baptist Theological Seminary, Lombard, Illinois, 1994 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - "Preaching Renewed by Paul's Romans" -Eleventh Annual Florida Winter Pastor's School, Stetson University, DeLand, Florida, 1996 February 6-9 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Preaching Renewed by Paul's Romans" -Eleventh Annual Florida Winter Pastor's School, Stetson University, DeLand, Florida (Correspondence only), 1996 Feb 6-9 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Biblical Witness to the Character of God" - East Ohio Conference, Lorain, Ohio, 1996 July 29- August 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Seminary Professor as Scholar" - Achtemeier Retirement, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2a)
  - OMSC - Seminar on the Gospels, New Haven, CT, 1998 November 2-6 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Spiritual Dimensions of Caregiving" - Connecticut Alzheimer's Association, 2000 April 28 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "The Adams Era" (retirement of Harry Adams), 2000 May 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "What Has Jesus Got to Do With Us? Three New Testament Answers" - The Dillard Forum of Trinity United Methodist Church, Richmond, VA, 2006 Nov (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Baptism of Jesus" - Lecture Tübingen, no date (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Christ and Salvation", no date (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Instead of Christendom", no date (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Luke", no date (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Mark", no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Matthew", no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "N.T. Understanding of Man", no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Paradigm Conflicts in Early Christianity" - Conference on Christianity and Culture: Continuing Conflict - Hartwick College, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "What is N.T Today?", 1960s (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Writings, Series II
  - School Work
    - New Testament, Andover Newton, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "The Parousia and Daily Life" for New Testament Eschatology, Dr. Paul S. Minear, 1952 January 18 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Alleged Aramaic in the Acts: A Preliminary Study, 1954 October 18 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - The Art Vocabulary from Jewish Epitaphs in Rome (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Romans 7: Paul or not Paul, Christian or Non-Christian (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Papers and Articles
    - "The Confession and Commission of Simon: Matt. 16:13-20", Foundations: A Baptist Journal of History and Theology, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "The Work of the Critic in the Work of the Church" in Koinonia, Vanderbilt Divinity School, Volume VII, Number 3, 1963 March (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - "Bonkerkamm's Jesus of Nazareth Revisited" in The Journal of Religion, Vol. 49, No.1 Jan 1969, The University of Chicago; and "Which Way to Jesus of Nazareth" in Foundations, April 1962, 1962 April, 1969 January (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Book Reviews - Manuscripts Published, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "Where the NT Came From" for Classmate, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Problems of NT Theology: A Critique of Alan Richardson's An Introduction to the New Testament Theology" in Novum Testamentum, Vol. VII, Fasc. 3, 1964, E. J. Brill, Leiden (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Publications in Adult Teacher and Adult Leader, 1964-1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "John the Baptist in Christianized Gnosticism" in Initiation, Contributions to the Theme of the Study-Conference of the International Association for the History of Religions held at Strasburg, Leiden Brill, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Mark 3:7-12 and Mark's Christology" - Reprint from Journal of Biblical Literature, Vol LXXXIV, Part IV, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Jesus' Entrance Upon His Mission: Luke 3:1-4:30" in Review and Expositor, Gospel of Luke, Vol. LXIV, No. 4, Fall, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "The Bible's Authority Today" in The Christian Home, Methodist, 1969 February (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Speaking of Jesus" - Board of Education, United Methodist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, 1969 March (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "The Sermon on the Mount", 1970 April (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "On Suffering" - for the Board of Education, United Methodist Church, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Theological Ethics in an American Crisis" from Interpretation, Volume XXIV, No. 4, 1970 October (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "The Church, the New Testament, and Violence" in Pastoral Psychology, 1971 October (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Christology: A Future?" by Peter C. Hodgson and Leander E. Keck, Abingdon Press, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)